<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<metadata>
    <name>Cadaver: The Rotten Expansion</name>
    <directory>cadaver</directory>
    <id>2508822241</id>
    <description>Cadaver is a mod for The Binding of Isaac: Repentance that adds 7 new unlocks and 1 new playable character! Explore the basement with Cadaver, Isaac's rotting corpse, and gain access to Golden Souls, Rotten Chests, and more!

- CADAVER -

Cadaver only has one rotten eye, so he can only fire at a fixed 1.5 tears per second. All tear pickups are converted to an equivalent damage multiplier.

Cadaver can only obtain Rotten Hearts and Bone Hearts. Any red hearts that spawn are converted to Rotten Hearts, with a rare chance to convert into a Bone Heart.

Cadaver can pickup soul hearts, but they are immediately removed to spawn friendly critters!

Birthright turns all current and future blue flies into locusts!

Cadaver starts with Yuck Heart. Use it in combat or in Curse Rooms to hold on to your bone hearts.

- UNLOCKS -

Vestments (Defeat Isaac and ??? as Cadaver)
[Angel Room] Gain a random Angel Room item effect in every room.

Probiotics (Defeat Satan and The Lamb as Cadaver)
[Trinket] If Isaac has a Rotten Heart, gain a moderate stat boost.

Soul of Cadaver (Defeat Hush as Cadaver)
Spawns friendly leeches, friendly maggots, a bone heart, and rotten hearts.

Cadaver's Left Eye (Defeat Delirium as Cadaver)
[Treasure Room] Increased Damage. Fixes fire rate at 1.5 and converts all tear ups into an equivalent damage multiplier.

Forbidden Fruit (Defeat Mother as Cadaver)
[Devil Room] When used, gain a permanent damage multiplier and tear delay reduction. Once used, Isaac takes periodic damage until the end of the run (persists through resurrections).

Golden Soul (Defeat Beast as Cadaver)
Activates a random soul effect. Has a chance to spawn another Golden Soul upon use.

Rotten Chests (Defeat Mega Satan as Cadaver)
Rarely, a normal chest will be replaced with a rotten variant that gives some additonal rotten-themed pickups. Also a chance to spawn a rotten pedestal item!

- AUTHOR'S NOTE -

A lot of the stuff I'm trying to do in this mod isn't super well supported by the modding framework. There are some quirks in the implementation (like achievement unlocks appearing instantly instead of in between floors). I've tried recreating the base game look and feel but there will almost certainly be holes.

- MORE INFO -

To just play Cadaver (without any unlocks), install this mod instead: https://steamcommunity.com/sharedfiles/filedetails/?id=2509303609

For full details, see the GitHub: https://github.com/Synthian/IsaacCadaver/blob/master/README.md</description>
    <version>1.7</version>
    <visibility>Public</visibility>
    <tag id="Lua"/>
    <tag id="Items"/>
    <tag id="Active Items"/>
    <tag id="Trinkets"/>
    <tag id="Pickups"/>
    <tag id="Player Characters"/>
    <tag id="Graphics"/>
</metadata>
